THE STUDENT OF PRAGUE made film history in 1913 as one of the first " artist films , "
for the premiere of which a score was composed .
The film was exported to many countries
and helped establish the worldwide reputation of German silent films .
Sadly , the film only survived in a re-edited version from 1926
and abridged English-language versions for foreign markets .
It wasn 't until 1987
that the first attempt at a reconstruction of the original version
was undertaken under the direction of Dr Wilfried Kugel .
This new digital reconstruction by the Filmmuseum München is based on the outline by Hanns Heinz Ewers ,
the original piano score by Josef Weiss and contemporary reviews .
The German intertitles have been re-set according to historical templates .
Judging from the duration listed by the censorship office in 1913 ( 1,548 metres , 85 minutes ) ,
the film is still missing roughly two minutes of footage .
The instances of missing pictures are replaced with short periods of black frames .
Musical prelude and interlude were already without pictures in the original .
The Student of Prague
A Romantic Drama in Four Acts by HANNS HEINZ EWERS .
Screenplay by the author .
- - Text translated and subtitles synced by darthfrede - -
CAST OF CHARACTERS :
Balduin , a student
Scapinelli , an old adventurer
Lyduschka , a traveling girl
Countess Margit von Schwarzenberg
Count Schwarzenberg , her father
Baron Waldis-Schwarzenberg , her cousin and fiancé .
Author and leading actor in historical Prague , where the story will be played out .
ACT I.
" Long live Balduin ,
the best swordsman of Prague and its most audacious student ! "
" I 'm ruined !
If only I had a great fortune or a rich heiress . "
Countess Margit and her fiancé set out on a par force hunt .
" My dear cousin ,
I will obey my father 's wishes , but I do not love you . "
The Countess slips her locket to Balduin .
Balduin 's student lodgings .
Balduin pays a visit to the Count .
I hereby certify that I was paid 100,000 guilder .
In exchange , I give Mister Scapinelli
the right to take from this room whatever pleases him .
Prague , May 13 , 1820 .
... the right to take from this room whatever pleases him .
Prague , May 13 , 1820 . Balduin
END OF ACT I.
ACT II .
Balduin is invited to a ball at the governor 's palace .
" Who are you ? "
I am no god nor a demon ,
but the one who once scornfully called me by your name
spoke the truth !
The Countess in her drawing room .
Countess , I beg you to keep your word !
Eleven o 'clock tomorrow night , meet me at the Jewish Cemetery .
It is the most secluded place in town and no one will see us there .
Balduin
END OF ACT II .
Musical Interlude
ACT III .
Countess Margit leaves for the rendezvous .
" With swords ? But Balduin is the best swordsman in Prague . "
" Spare him !
He is my sister 's only child , my daughter 's fiancé , my heir and the last to carry our name . "
Balduin goes to the duel .
The deed he would not commit , the other committed .
END OF ACT III .
ACT IV .
Everywhere where I wanted to sleep , everywhere where I wanted to die ,
everywhere where I waited another day , on my way I met a passer-by ,
a pilgrim in everything black , resembling me like a brother !
( Alfred de Musset )
" Mister Balduin is no longer permitted to see the Count and the Lady . "
Giving himself over to dance and play , Balduin seeks to forget his love .
" Dare you also play against me ? "
Balduin wants to see his beloved once more .
I am no god nor a demon ,
but the one who once scornfully called me by your name
spoke the truth !
Where you are , I too will always be ,
and on your final hour , by the stone on your grave I will sit .
( Alfred de Musset )
Here lies Balduin
The End .